Guide to the William Coleman research files CBHM.0032
Center for Brooklyn History
- Series 2: Secondary sources, 1900-2021
  - Sub-series 2.1: Articles, 1900-2021 (Box 4, Folder A-P, Box 5, Folder R-Y)
    Rippy, J. Fred, Diplomacy of the United States and Mexico Regarding the Isthmus of Tehuantepec, 1848-1860. The Mississippi Valley Historical Review 6.4, March 1920.
    Rippy, J. Fred, Anglo-American Filibusters and the Gadson Treaty. The Hispanic American Historical Review 5.2, May 1922.
    Roberts, William I., III, Samuel Storke: An Eighteenth-Century London Merchant Trading to the American Colonies. The Business History Review 39.2, Summer 1965.
    Robson Hay, Thomas. Gazaway Bugg Lamar, Confederate Banker and Business Man. The Georgia Historical Quarterly 37.2, June 1953.
    Rodriguez, J. Javier, The US-Mexican War in James Lowell's The Biglow Papers. Arizona Quarterly 63.3, Autumn 2007.
    Rommel-Ruiz, W. Bryan, Colonizing the Black Atlantic: The African Colonization Movements in Postwar Rhode Island and Nova Scotia. Slavery and Abolition 27.3, December 2006.
    Rose, Jane F., Expanding Woman's Sphere, Dismantling Class, and Building Community: The Feminism of Elizabeth Oakes Smith. CLA Journal 45.2, December 2001.
    Rothstein, Richard, Books Often Give History a Facelift. The New York Times, October 2 2002.
    Rutman, Darrett B., Governor Winthrop's Garden Crop: The Significance of Agriculture in the Early Commerce of Massachusetts Bay. The William and Mary Quarterly 20.3, July 1963.
    Salas, Antonion, Angel Carracedo, Martin Richards and Vincent Macauley, Charting the Ancestry of African Americans (Report). American Journal of Human Genetics 77.4, October 2005.
    Scherman, Timothy H., "Onward!" New Paths of Inquiry for the Future of Oakes Smith Studies. Society for the Study of Women Writers Conference, November 2006.
    Schlesinger, Arthur M. Jr., The Problem of Richard Hildreth. The New England Quarterly 13.2, June 1940.
    Schorsch, Jonathan, American Jewish Historians, Colonial Jews and Blacks, and the Limits of Wissenschaft: A Critical Review. Jewish Social Studies 6.2, Winter 2000.
    Schroeder, John H., Major Jack Downing and American Expansionism: Seba Smith's Political Satire, 1847-1856. The New England Quarterly 50.2, June 1977.
    Scroggins, Mark. Georgia, New York, and Muskets on the Eve of the Civil War. The Georgia Historical Quarterly 89.3, Fall 2005.
    Scroggs, William O., William Walker's Designs on Cuba. The Mississippi Valley Historical Review 1.2, September 1914.
    Scudder, Harold, A Note on Major Jack Downing. The New England Quarterly 11.3, September 1938.
    Senechal, Roberta, A Respectable Rebel: Elizabeth Oakes Smith and the Dilemma of Victorian Feminism. University of Virginia lecture draft, 1985.
    Shaw, Wayne, The Plymouth Pulpit: Henry Ward Beecher's Slave Auction Block. ATQ (The American Transcendental Quarterly) 14.4, December 2000.
    Sheridan, R.B., The Commercial and Financial Organization of the British Slave Trade, 1750-1807. The Economic History Review 11.2, 1958.
    Sherwood, Marika, Perfidious Albion: Britain, the USA, and Slavery in the 1840s and 1860s. Contributions in Black Studies 13, 1995.
    Sherwood, Marika, Britain, the slave trade and slavery, 1808-1843. Race and Class 46.2, October-December 2004.
    Shillingburg, Patricia and Edward, The Disposition of Slaves on East End of Long Island from 1680 to 1796, 2003.
    Shorto, Russell, All Political Ideas are Local: Why Liberalism and Most Other American Ways of Thinking About Politics Have Their Roots in Manhattan. The New York Times Magazine, October 2 2005.
    Smallwood, Arwin D., A History of Native American and African Relations from 1502 to 1900. Negro History Bulletin, April-September 1999.
    Smith, Lucille Arthur, The Oaksmith Saga. Prepared for the Carteret County Historical Society meeting, 1960.
    Smythe, Augustine T. and Sister Sue. Excerpts from the Wartime Correspondence of Augustine T. Smythe. The South Carolina Historical Magazine 62.1, January 1961.
    Solow, Barbara L., The Transatlantic Slave Trade: A New Census. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.1, 2001.
    Spector, Robert M., Lincoln and Taney: A Study in Consitutional Polarization. The American Journal of Legal History 15.3, July 1971.
    Staples, Brent, Slaves in the Family: One Generation's Shame is Another's Revelation. The New York Times, June 15 2003.
    Steward, Irvin, American Treaty Provisions Relating to Consular Privileges and Immunities. The American Journal of International Law 20.1, January 1926.
    Straysbaugh, John, On the Trail of Brooklyn's Underground Railroad. The New York Times, October 12 2007.
    Stryker-Rodda, Harriet Mott, Brooklyn and Long Island Sanitary Fair 1864. Journal of Long Island History 4.1, 1964.
    Swan, Robert J., John Teasman: African-American Educator and the Emergence of Cmomunity in Early Black New York City, 1787-1815. Journal of the Early Republic 12.3, Autumn 1992.
    Swan, Robert J., First Africans into New Netherland, 1625 or 1626? Halve Maen 66, Winter 1993.
    Swan, Robert J., The Other Fort Amsterdam: New Light on Aspects of Slavery in New Netherland. Afro-Americans in New York Life and History 22.2, July 31 1998.
    Sweeney, Kevin, Early American Religious Traditions: Native Visions and Christian Providence. OAH Magazine of History 22.1, January 2008.
    Talbot, Margaret, Supreme Confidence: The Jurisprudence of Justice Antonin Scalia. The New Yorker, March 28, 2005.
    TePaske, John Jay, Appleton Oaksmith, Filibuster Agent. The North Carolina Historical Review 35, January-October 1958.
    Thomas, Robert Paul and Richard Nelson Bean, Fishers of Men: The Profits of the Slave Trade. The Journal of Economic History 34.4, December 1974.
    Thornton, John, Cannibals, Witches, and Slave Traders in the Atlantic World. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.2, 2003. Tice, Pam, Enslaved African Americans in Bloomingdale. West Side Rag, May 29 2021.
    Treudley, Mary, The United States and Santo Domingo, 1789-1866. The Journal of Race Development 7.1, July 1916.
    Tuchinsky, Adam-Max, "The Bourgeousie Will Fall and Fall Forever": The New-York Tribune, the 1848 French Revolution, and American Social Democratic Discourse. The Journal of American History 92.2, September 2005.
    Tuchinsky, Adam, "Woman and Her Needs": Elizabeth Oakes Smith and the Divorce Question. Journal of Women's History 28.1, Spring 2016.
    Van Cleve, George, Forum: Somerset's Case Revisited: Somerset's Case and Its Antecedents in Imperial Perspective. Law and History Review 24.3, Fall 2006.
    Vink, Marcus, "The world's oldest trade": Dutch slavery and slave trade in the Indian Ocean in the seventeenth century. Journal of World History 14.2, June 2003.
    Vitello, Paul, From Stand in Long Island Slavery Case, a Snapshot of a Hidden U.S. Problem. The New York Times, December 3 2007.
    Wagman, Morton, The Rise of Pieter Claessen Wyckoff: Social Mobility on the Colonial Frontier. New York History, January 1972.
    Wagman, Morton, Corporate Slavery in New Netherland. The Journal of Negro History 65.1, Winter 1980.
    Wakeman, Frederic, Jr., Voyages. The American Historical Review 98.1, February 1993.
    Walters, Rebekah Velsor, Walt Whitman. Journal of Long Island History 2.1, 1940.
    Warren, Wendy Anne, "The Cause of her Grief": The Rape of a Slave in Early New England. The Journal of American History 93.4, March 2007.
    Wax, Darold D., Negro Resistance to the Early American Slave Trade. The Journal of Negro History 51.1, January 1966.
    Wax, Darold D., Preference for Slaves in Colonial America. The Journal of Negro History 58.4, October 1973.
    Wesley, Charles H., Manifests of Slave Shipments Along the Waterways, 1808-1864. The Journal of Negro History 27.2, April 1942.
    Whitfield, Henry Amani, The American Background of Loyalist Slaves. Left History 14.1, 2009.
    Wiecek, William M., Slavery and Abolition Before the United States Supreme Court 1820-1860. Journal of American History 65, 1978.
    Wikipedia, Lewsi Tappan. Wikipedia, accessed 2006.
    Williams, Oscar R., The Regimentation of Blacks on the Urban Frontier in Colonial Albany, New York City and Philadelphia. The Journal of Negro History 63.4, October 1978.
    Williams-Meyers, A.J., Positioning and imaging Caesar: from margin to center in the historiography of colonial New York City. Afro-Americans in New York Life and History 28.2, July 2004.
    Wiltenburg, Joy, Excerpts from the Diary of Elizabeth Oakes Smith. Signs 9.3, Spring 1984.
    Wish, Harvey, The Revival of the African Slave Trade in the United States, 1856-1860. The Mississippi Valley Historical Review 27.4, March 1941.
    Woidat, Caroline M., Puritan Daughters and "Wild" Indians: Elizabeth Oakes Smith's Narratives of Domestic Captivity. Legacy: A Journal of American Women Writers 18.1, 2001.
    Wood, J. Taylor, The Capture of a Slaver. Atlantic Monthly 86, 1900.
    Yoshpe, Harry B., Record of Slave Manumissions in New York During the Colonial and Early National Periods. The Journal of Negro History 26.1, January 1941.
    Yoshpe, Harry B., Record of Slave Manumissions in Albany, 1800-28. The Journal of Negro History 26.4, October 1941.
    Younger, Karen Fisher, Liberia and the Last Slave Ships. Civil War History 54.4, 2008.
  - Sub-series 2.2: Books and book excerpts, 1901-2008 (Box 5)
    - Books and book excerpts by author surname
      Alexander, De Alva Stanwood. A Political History of the State of New York (Volume II, 1833-1861), pp.351-352. New York: Henry Holt & Co., 1906
      Beard, Charles A.. An Economic Interpretation of the Constitution of the United States, pp.176-177. New York: The Macmillan Company, 1956
      Bennett, Norman R., George E. Brooks Jr., eds.. New England Merchants in Africa: A History Through Documents 1802 to 1865, p. 104. Boston: Boston University Press, 1965
      Blaustein, Albert P. and Robert L. Zanrando, eds.. Civil Rights and the American Negro: A Documentary History, pp. 4-7, 22-27, 36-41. New York: Washington Square Press, 1970
      Block, W.T.. Chapter IV: Filibustering, Piracy and the African Slave Trade. A History of Jefferson County, Texas, 1976
      Brasseaux, Carl A. and Glenn R. Conrad, eds.. The Road to Louisiana: The Saint-Domingue Refugees, 1792-1809, pp. 92-101, 166-171. The Center for Louisiana Studies, 1992
      Burak, H. Paul. History of the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York. New York: Federal Bar Association of New York, New Jersey, and Connecticut, 1962
      Burrows, Edwin G. and Mike Wallace. In the Kingdom of Sugar. Excerpt published in South Street Magazine from Gotham: A History of New York City to 1898. Oxford University Press, 1998
      Corbitt, Duvon Chough. A Study of the Chinese in Cuba, 1847-1947. Wilmore, KY: Asbury College Press, 1971
      The Cuba Commission. The Cuba Commission Report: A Hidden History of the Chinese in Cuba. Baltimore, MD: Johns Hopkins University Press, 1993
      Custer, E.A.. A synoptical History of the Towns of Kings County from 1525 to Modern Times. New York, Sherwood's, 1911
      Davis, Thomas J.. A Rumor of Revolt: The "Great Negro Plot" in Colonial New York. New York: The Free Press, 1985
      Day, Lydia S.. Making a Way to Freedom: A History of African Americans on Long Island. New York: Empire States Books, circa 2000
      Deschamps, Hubert. Histoire de Madagascar pp.65-66, 76-78, 320. Paris: Editions Berger-Levrault, 1965
      Dewey, Mary E.. Orville Dewey (1794-1882). In Eliot, Samuel Atkins, ed. Heralds of a Liberal Faith, Volume III: The Preachers. Boston: American Unitarian Association, 1910
      Dictionary of American Biography. Gazaway Bugg Lamar. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1936
      Dugdale, Antony, J.J. Fueser and J. Celso de Castro Alves. Yale, Slavery and Aboliton. The Amistad Committee, 2001
      Eltis, David. Extending the Frontiers: Essays on the New Transatlantic Slave Trade Database. New Haven: Yale University Press, 2008
      Emerson, Donald E.. Richard Hildreth [biography]. Baltimore, MD: The Johns Hopkins Press, 1946
      Emmer, P.C.. Chapter 5: The West India Company, 1621-1791: Dutch or Atlantic? In Blusse, Leonard and Femme Gaastra, eds. Companies and Trade. Leiden University Press, 1981
      Faber, Eli. Slavery and the Jews: A Historical Inquiry. Hunter College Jewish Social Studies Program, Occasional Papers in Jewish History and Thought No. 2, 1994
      Faber, Eli. Jews, Slaves, and the Slave Trade: Setting the Record Straight. New York: New York University Press, 1998
      Ford, Paul Leicester, ed.. Pamphlets on the Constitution of the United States Published During Its Discussion by the People 1787-1788, pp. 329-333, 366-371, 378-379. New York: Burt Franklin, 1971
      Fritz, Chritian G.. Federal Justice in California: The Court of Ogden Hoffman, 1851-1891, pp.10-11, 21, 269, 272. Lincoln, NE: University of Nebraska Press, 1991
      Christopher Fyfe. A History of Sierra Leone, pp.150-151, 194-197. Oxford University Press, 1962
      Gordon, John D. III.. The Trial of the Officers and Crew of the Schooner "Savannah." Second Circuit Historical Committee pamphlet, 1983
      Gordon, John Steele. The Great Game: The Emergence of Wall Street as a World Power, 1653-2000. New York: Scribner, 1999
      Gouverneu, Marian. As I Remember: Recollections of American Society During the Nineteenth Century, pp.69-71. New York: D. Appleton and Company, 1911
      Greenhalgh, Albion Robert. Sources Cited in The Rise of New York Port [1815-1860]. New York: Scribner, 1939
      Hemstreet, Charles. The Story of Manhattan. 1901
      Hemstreet, Charles. Literary New York, Its Landmarks and Associations, pp.197-201. New York: Putnam, 1903
      Henry, Alice. The Trade Union Woman. 1915
      Hershkowitz, Leo. Wills of Early New York Jews, 1704-1799, pp. xi-xvi, 5-6, 8-10, 15-17, 21-23, 44-46, 55-56, 59-61, 65-66, 79--81, 84-88, 129, 135-136, 158-159, 161, 208. New York: American Jewish Historical Society, 1967
      Hunt, Gaillard, ed.. The Writings of James Madison…Volume IV: 1787, The Journal of the Consitutional Convention, pp.300-303. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1903
      Ireland, Ralph R.. Slavery on Long Island: A Study of Economic Motivation. Brooklyn: Long Island Historical Society, 1966
      Jameson, John Franklin. Privateering and Piracy in the Colonial Period: Illustrative Documents, pp.14-17, 175-187, 189-199, 220-223, 235, 318-322, 378-415. New York: The Macmillan Company, 1923
      Judge, John H. "Memorial of George P. Andrews." In Association of the Bar of the City of New York, Annual Reports, Charter, Constitution, By-Laws..., 1904.
      Kolchin, Peter. American Slavery 1619-1877, pp.2627, 256-257. New York: Hill and Wang, 2003
      Kupperman, Karen Ordahl. The Jamestown Project, pp.288, 329, 364. Cambridge: The Belknap Press of Harvard University Press, 2007
      LaChance, Paul F. The 1809 Immigration of Saint-Domingue Refugees to New Orleans: Reception, Integration and Impact. In Brasseaux, Carl A., ed. The Louisiana Purchase Bicentennial Series in Louisiana History, Volume X: A Refuge for All Ages: Immigration in Louisiana History. Lafayette, LA: Center for Louisiana Studies, University of Southwestern Louisiana, 1996
      Lauber, Almon Wheeler. Chapter IV, pp.112-115, Chapter VII, p. 193,Chapter IX: Property Relations, pp. 211-241, and Chapter XII, p. 290. In Indian Slavery in Colonial Times Within the Present Limits of the United States. New York: Columbia University, 1913
      Lewis, Roberts G.. Geraldine Oaksmith: Real Estate Developer, Eccentric Recluse---Research Chemist? Morehead City, NC: Carteret County Historical Society, 1997
      Linder, Marc, & Zacharias, Lawrence S. Of Cabbages and Kings County: Agriculture and the Formation of Modern Brooklyn, pp.80-88, 364-367. Iowa City: University of Iowa Press, 1999
      Lubbock, Basil. Coolie Ships and Oil Sailers. Glasgow: Brown, Son & Ferguson, 1935
      Malloy, William M., compiler. Treaties, Conventons, International Acts, Protocols and Agreements between the United States and Other Powers, 1776-1909, Volume II, p.1458. Washington, DC: Government Printing Office, 1910
      Marcus, Jacob R.. Chapter 37: The Slave Trade. In The Colonial American Jew, 1492-1776. Detroit: Wayne State University Press, 1970
      May, Robert E.. Manifest Destiny's Underworld: FIlibustering in Antebellum America, pp.174-177, 358-359. Chapel Hill, NC: University of North Carolina Press, 2002
      Miller, Joseph C.. The Story of the Atlantic Slave Trade: 1440-1870. The Journal of American History
      Moore, John Bassett. A Digest of International Law…Volume V, pp.19-21, 81. Washington, DC: Government Printing Office, 1906
      Morris, Richard B.. Selected Cases of the Mayor Court of the City of New York, 1674-1784. Washington, D.C.: The American Historical Association, 1935
      Phillips, Ulrich Bonnell. American Negro Slavery, A Survey of the Supply, Employment and Control of Negro Labor as Determined by the Plantation Regime. New York: Appleton, 1929
      Pierce, J. Kingston. The Magician of San Francisco. Excerpted from San Francisco, You're History, 1995
      Ratner, Lorman. Powder Keg: Northern Opoosition to the Antislavery Movement 1831-1840, pp.20-21, 26-27. New York: Basic Books, Inc., 1966
      The Researcher 14.1 Spring-Summer 1998 [Elizabeth Oakes Smith issue]
      Robbins, Christine Chapman. David Hosack, Citizen of New York, pp.62-65. Philadelphia: The American Philosphical Society, 1964
      Roche, Emma Langdon. Historic Sketches of the South. New York: The Knickerbocker Press, 1914
      Sandbeck, Peter B.. The Historic Architecture of New Bern and Craven County, North Carolina, p.108. New Bern, NC: The Tryon Palace Commission, 1988
      Smyth, Thomas. Autobiographical Notes, Letters and Reflections, pp. 587--607. Charleston, SC: Walker, Evans & Cogswell Company, 1914
      Spears, John D.. Appendix A:…vessels arrested and bonded from…1852, to…1862. In The American Slave Trade. London: Bickers & Son, 1901
      Strange, Douglas C.. Patterns of Antislavery among American Unitarians, 1831-1860, pp.180-183, 218-227. Rutherford, NJ: Fairleigh Dickinson University Press, 1977
      Sullivan, James, ed.. The History of New York State, Book II, Chapter II, Part IV. Lewis Historical Publishing Company, 1927
      United States Bureau of the Census. Chapter XIV: Statistics of Slaves. In A Century of Population Growth. Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, 1909
      Wakeman, Abram. History and Reminscences of Lower Wall Street and Vicinity, pp.20-25, 52-54. New York: The Spice Mill Publishing Co., 1914
      Wyatt-Brown, Betram. Lewis Tappan and the Evangelical War Against Slavery, 178-181, 184-185, 328-331, 342-343. Cleveland: The Press of Case Western Reserve University, 1969
    - Selected Rensselaerswijck Seminar Papers
      A Beautiful and Fruitful Place: Selected Rensselaerswijck Seminar Papers, Volume I. Albany, NY: New Netherland Project, 1991.
      Burke, Thomas. The New Netherland Fur Trade, 1657-1661: Response to Crisis.
      Goodfriend, Joyce D. Black Families in New Netherland.
      Matson, Cathy. The 'Hollander Interest' and Ideas about Free Trade in Colonial New York: Persistent Influences of the Dutch, 1884-1764.
      Rink, Oliver A. New Netherland and the Amsterdam Merchants Unraveling a Secret Colonialism.
      Starna, William A. Seventeenth Century Dutch-Indian Trade A Perspective from Iroquoia.
      Wilcoxen, Charlotte. Dutch Trade with New England.
  - Sub-series 2.3: Indexes, lists and guides (Box 6)
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Afrigenes.com Inward Slave Manifests
      Slave shipping manifests. McClendon, Alma. Inward Slave Manifests for the Port of New Orleans, Roll 12 1837-1839.
    - Afro-Louisiana History and Genealogy 1718-1820
      Hall, Gwendolyn Mildo. Slavery and African Ethnicities in the Americas.
    - Alan Singer teaching materials on slavery in NY state
    - Black Loyalists website
      Canadian site; Black loyalist directory. Interesting comparison to Graham Russell Hodge's book on escaping.
    - Brooklyn Historical Society
      BobCat information on slavery, finding aids for autograph manuscript collections, Onderdonk guide.
    - Census slave data by county 1820-1860
    - Gilder Lehrman Center resources
    - Map reproductions
      Photocopies of insurance and zoning maps of sections of Brooklyn, dates unknown, likely late 19th-early 20th centuries.
    - Mystic Seaport Museum
      Records of Thomas Dunham's Newphew & Company, Coll. 196, Manuscripts Collection, G.W. Blunt White Library.
    - National Archives resources
    - New Netherland Institute resources
    - New York Public Library resources
    - New York State Council for the Social Studies teaching guide
      New York and Slavery: Complicity and Resistence.
    - New York to New Orleans slave manifests, 1807-1860
    - New-York Historical Society resources
      Slavery in New York exhibition.
    - Race, Racism, and the Law website
      Randall, Venellia R. Slavery federal cases, 1790-1865.
    - Schuyler family genealogy
      Descendents of the Schuyler Family Including Bayards and Livingstons.
    - Slave trade laws (federal) background materials
    - Supreme Court Historical Society journal index
    - The American People companion website
      Slave Trade Documents--inventory.
    - TheShipsList website
      Swiggum, S. and M. Kohli. Settlers to Liberia (1843-187?) [information taken from The African Repository, and Colonial Journal, 1843-1867]. Emigrant Ships to the West Indies in the 1850s.
    - The Trans-Atlantic Slave Trade Database
      Eltis, David. Table of Contents and sources, Analysis of data.
    - University of Georgia
      Guide to the Gazaway Bugg Lamar papers, MS 10. Hargrett Book and Manuscript Library, University of Georgia Libraries.
    - University of Pennsylvania resource list
      University of Pennsylvania Dept. of History. The Crisis of the Union: An Electronic Archive of Documents about the Causes, Conduct, and Consequences of the US Civil War
    - Virginia Slave Trade in the Eighteenth Century guide
      Klein, Herbert S. "Virginia Slave Trade in the Eighteenth Century" 1727-1769: A User's Guide to the Machine Readable Data File Study Description
  - Sub-series 2.4: Reviews, 1928-2018 (Box 6)
    Appiah, Kwame Anthony, What Was Africa to Them? [review of The Door of No Return by William St. Clair, Middle Passages by James T. Campbell, American Africans in Ghana by Kevin K. Gaines, Black Gold of the Sun by Ekow Eshun, and Lose Your Mother by Saidiya Hartman]. The New York Review, September 27 2007.
    Berlin, Ira, Slaves in the Family [review of Inhuman Bondage by David Brion Davis]. New York Times Book Review, May 14 2006.
    Berry, Jason, Urban Gumbo [review of The World that Made New Orleans by Ned Sublette]. The New York Times, February 17 2008.
    Blouet, Olwyn M., Reviews of Books: Apprenticing to Freedom in the West Indies [review of Between Slavery and Freedom, ed. Roderick A. McDonald, and A Narrative of Events, ed. Diana Paton]. The William and Mary Quarterly 59.3, July 2002.
    Bodle, Wayne, Reviews of Books [review of Cadwallader Colden: A Figure of the American Enlightenment by Alfred R. Hoermann]. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.2, April 2003.
    Brewer, John, The Irish Indian Chief [review of White Savage: William Johnson and the Invention of America by Fintan O'Toole]. The New York Review of Books, December 1 2005.
    Buhle, Paul, [Review of] The Rise and Fall of the White Republic: Class Politics and Mass Culture in Nineteenth Century America by Alexander Saxton. The Nation 252.23, June 17 1991.